{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Foal","incorrectAnswers":["Tiger","Kitten","Giraffe"],"question":"What is the meaning of the name of the constellation Equuleus?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Wise Men","incorrectAnswers":["Musicians","Revolutionary Leaders","Terrorists"],"question":"Who were Balthazar, Melchior and Caspar?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Iron Maiden","incorrectAnswers":["The Brass Bull","The Infernus Cage","The Hinged Hell"],"question":"Which Instrument Of Torture Had a Hinged Case Full Of Spikes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Shape of Water","incorrectAnswers":["Call Me by Your Name","Darkest Hour","Dunkirk"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2017?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Clive Sinclair","incorrectAnswers":["Tim Berners Lee","Alan Sugar","Bill Gates"],"question":"Who Invented The ZX80, The First Widely Available Personal Computer?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Alexander Fleming","incorrectAnswers":["Louis Pasteur","Frederick Sanger","John Dalton"],"question":"Who Is Accepted As The Discoverer Of Penicillin?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"old age","incorrectAnswers":["life","the nature of values and value judgements","ticks and mites"],"question":"What is Gerontology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Acacia","incorrectAnswers":["Acer","Willow","Redbud"],"question":"What type of tree has an umbrella-shaped canopy and is native to Africa and Australasia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Apricot ","incorrectAnswers":["Raspberry","Orange","Banana"],"question":"Laetrile is associated with the which fruit?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Greek philosopher","incorrectAnswers":["Ottoman Emperor.","Roman General.","Spiritual teacher and central figure of Christianity."],"question":"Which of the following describes Aristotle?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Photosynthesis","incorrectAnswers":["Osmosis","Thesis","Carditis"],"question":"By what process do plants manufacture energy?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Gibson","incorrectAnswers":["Ursula K. Le Guin","Edgar Rice Burroughs","Margaret Atwood"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Sprawl trilogy'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Bubonic","incorrectAnswers":["Septicemic","Pneumonic","Laryngeal"],"question":"What Type Of Plague Was The Black Death?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Help!'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Koskenkorva Viina","incorrectAnswers":["Schnapps","Rakia","Sang Som Rum"],"question":"Which of these is a popular drink in Finland?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I could do this all day\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"There's no crying in baseball!\"","\"If you build it, he will come.\"","\"Toga! Toga!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Captain America: Civil War'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Maël Foulon","incorrectAnswers":["Émile Zola","Alphonse Daudet","Alexandre Dumas"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Gargantua and Pantagruel'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Brandon Sanderson","incorrectAnswers":["H. P. Lovecraft","Stephenie Meyer","Stephen King"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Wheel of Time'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"York and Lancaster","incorrectAnswers":["Stark and Lannister","Tudor and Stuart","Hapsberg and Victoria"],"question":"The Wars of the Roses (1455-85) were fought between which two houses of England?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The T-Birds","incorrectAnswers":["The Wild Dogs","The Pink Ladies","The Heavy Quarters"],"question":"What Was The Gang Name Of John Travolta And His Cohorts In The Movie Grease?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Triple Jump","incorrectAnswers":["Long Jump","High Jump","Pole Vault"],"question":"Which athletics event consists of two hops and a jump?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Almaty","incorrectAnswers":["Karachi","Zaporozhye","Kharkov"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Kazakhstan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Dustin Hoffman","incorrectAnswers":["Dan Aykroyd","Gérard Depardieu","Shah Rukh Khan"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including Rain Man and Lemony Snicket's A Series of Unfortunate Events?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Grey's Anatomy","incorrectAnswers":["House","ER","Chicago Med"],"question":"Which medical TV drama is set in a Seattle hospital?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Saturday Night Fever","incorrectAnswers":["Midnight Cowboy","The Treasure of the Sierra Madre","On the Waterfront"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Tony Manero'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Apple","incorrectAnswers":["Mango","Peach","Plum"],"question":"Which of these fruits is not a drupe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cameroon","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","Egypt","China"],"question":"Which country's capital city is Yaounde?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Hullaballoo","incorrectAnswers":["Gardyloo","Cattywampus","Cattywampus"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'a commotion'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1789","incorrectAnswers":["1943","1215","1533"],"question":"When Did The Storming Of The Bastille Take Place?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Howards End","incorrectAnswers":["Catch-22","To the Lighthouse","The Stranger"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Margaret Schlegel'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kazakhstan","incorrectAnswers":["Iraq","Cabo Verde","Brunei"],"question":"Nur-Sultan is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"A wife","incorrectAnswers":["A vice president","A left foot","A signature"],"question":"What did President James Buchanan not have?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Rigatoni","incorrectAnswers":["Fettuccine","Macaroni","Capellini"],"question":"Which pasta's name means 'Large lined ones'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Kobe","incorrectAnswers":["Wagyu","Sashimi","Sushi"],"question":"What type of highly prized Japanese beef comes from cows that are massaged and fed beer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Weezer","incorrectAnswers":["LMFAO","Static-X","The Black Keys"],"question":"Which alternative rock band from the United States released the studio album 'Everything Will Be Alright in the End'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A withdrawn boy who communicates with spirits seeks the help of a child psychologist.","incorrectAnswers":["A secretly ruthless woman insinuates herself into the lives of an aging actor and her circle of theater friends.","A stand-up comedian embarks on a downward spiral that leads to the creation of an iconic villain.","A former Roman General seeks revenge against the emperor who murdered his family."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie The Sixth Sense?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Golf","incorrectAnswers":["Tennis","Boxing","Rugby"],"question":"With Which Sport Would You Associate Colin Montgomerie?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["Mongolia","India","Australia"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Beijing?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"In the future, a sadistic gang leader is imprisoned and volunteers for a conduct-aversion experiment, but it doesn't go as planned.","incorrectAnswers":["A Korean War veteran sets out to reform his neighbor who tried to steal his prized possession.","A private detective hired to expose an adulterer in 1930s Los Angeles finds himself caught up in a web of deceit, corruption, and murder.","Monoliths discovered in Africa generations ago lead mankind on an awesome journey to Jupiter, with the help the world's greatest supercomputer."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie A Clockwork Orange?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Koreanic","Sino-Tibetan","Austronesian"],"question":"The language 'Sinhalese' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Gall bladder","incorrectAnswers":["Kidney","Bowel","Spleen"],"question":"This organ is a small pouch that stores bile.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jack Nicholson","incorrectAnswers":["Walter Matthau","Al Pacino","Maximilian Schell"],"question":"Who won the 1975 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Randle Patrick McMurphy in One Flew over the Cuckoo's Nest?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Wood & Sound","incorrectAnswers":["Multiple & Sound","Wood & Tone","Multiple & Tone"],"question":"'Xylophone' Is Derived From The Greek Words For What?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Zero","incorrectAnswers":["Dash","Spitfire","Typhoon"],"question":"The Misubishi A6M fighter aircraft used by Japan in World War 2 was commonly known as what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Got to Be Real","incorrectAnswers":["What I Am","All My Life","Unbelievable"],"question":"Cheryl Lynn had a one hit wonder in 1979 with which song?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur C. Clarke","Isaac Newton","Enid Blyton"],"question":"Which author wrote 'King Lear'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Lackadaisical","incorrectAnswers":["Yarborough","Curmudgeon","Ratoon"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'lacking enthusiasm or determination'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Neoclassicism","incorrectAnswers":["Romanticism","Fauvism","Impressionism"],"question":"Which artistic style of the late eighteenth and early nineteenth centuries revived the order and harmony of ancient Greek and Roman art?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Che Guevara","incorrectAnswers":["Raul Castro","Simon Bolivar","Vladimir Lenin"],"question":"Which revolutionary icon was killed on 9th October 1967?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Black Sea ","incorrectAnswers":["The Mediterranean","The Dead Sea","The Aegean Sea"],"question":"Into Which Sea Does The river Danube Flow?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Osaka","incorrectAnswers":["Adelaide","Incheon","Gold Coast"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Japan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Marc Antony","incorrectAnswers":["Lepidus","Marcus Crassus","Pompey"],"question":"Which Roman killed himself after his defeat at Actium?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Beyoncé","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Drake","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Which American singer, actress and record producer released the song 'Me, Myself and I'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Burgundy ","incorrectAnswers":["Bordeaux","Alsace","Loire Valley"],"question":"Chablis comes from which French wine region?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Lion King","incorrectAnswers":["The Wizard of Oz","Joker","Rear Window"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'Simba and his father are targeted by his uncle, who wants to ascend the throne himself.'","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Afroasiatic","Sino-Tibetan","Uralic"],"question":"The language 'Bengali' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"parasites","incorrectAnswers":["crime","nutrition","the signification and application of words"],"question":"What is Parasitology the study of?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"John","incorrectAnswers":["Matthew","Mark","Luke"],"question":"Who is referred to in the New Testament as 'the disciple Jesus loved'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The Neanderthal","incorrectAnswers":["Homo erectus","Australopithecus","Homo habilis"],"question":"What prehistoric species of human was a rival to early modern humans?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jingle All The Way","incorrectAnswers":["The Santa Claus","I'll Be Home For Christmas","Jack Frost"],"question":"In which 1996 Christmas film does Arnold Schwarzenegger play a father trying to get the must have toy for his son?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"the eyes","incorrectAnswers":["bacteria","crayfish","signs"],"question":"What is Ophthalmology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Precious Metals","incorrectAnswers":["Radiation","Wind Strength","Acidity"],"question":"What Is Measured Using The Troy System?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Erich Maria Remarque","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Silverberg","Frederik Pohl","Mario Puzo"],"question":"Which author wrote 'All Quiet on the Western Front'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Odin","incorrectAnswers":["Thor","Loki","Freya"],"question":"Which Norse god had the Valkyries as handmaidens?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"How Bizarre","incorrectAnswers":["Kung Fu Fighting","Convoy","Hot Child in the City"],"question":"What song did OMC have a hit with in 1997?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sicily","incorrectAnswers":["Sardinia","Crete","Cyprus"],"question":"What is the largest island in the Mediterranean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sebastian Stan","incorrectAnswers":["Stellan Skarsgård","John Slattery","Jeff Goldblum"],"question":"Which actor plays the role of Bucky Barnes in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Ottoman Empire","incorrectAnswers":["The Seljuk Empire","The Safavid Empire","The Mughal Empire"],"question":"What was the name of the Empire founded by Osman I around 1300AD?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mecca","incorrectAnswers":["Tehran","Dubai","Riyadh"],"question":"To where do Muslims make pilgrimage?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Thailand","incorrectAnswers":["Vietnam","India","Myanmar"],"question":"The white elephant is the sacred animal of __________","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Makepeace Thackeray","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","François-René de Chateaubriand","Orhan Pamuk"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Vanity Fair'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Beowulf","incorrectAnswers":["Thor","Ragnar","Arthur"],"question":"What was the name of the mythical hero-king who slew Grendal?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Coldplay","incorrectAnswers":["Oasis","Radiohead","Pulp"],"question":"Which British band released the album 'Parachutes'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Finifugal","incorrectAnswers":["Groke","Gabelle","Salopettes"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'afraid of finishing anything'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Auguste Escoffier ","incorrectAnswers":["Jacque Pépin","Raymond Oliver","Marie-Antoine Carême"],"question":"Which famous French chef invented the Peach Melba in 1893?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mali","incorrectAnswers":["Sierra Leone","Liberia","Cape Verde"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Senegal?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Fleetwood Mac","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Young","ABBA","Elvis Costello"],"question":"Who Released The 70's Album 'Rumours'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"New York Giants","incorrectAnswers":["New York Predators","New York Raiders","New York Lions"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in New York?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"James Joyce","incorrectAnswers":["Samuel Beckett","Oscar Wilde","Jonathan Swift"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Ulysses'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Doha","incorrectAnswers":["Lima","Juba","Kampala"],"question":"What is the capital city of Qatar?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Dolphin","incorrectAnswers":["Turtle","Lion","Gorilla"],"question":"Apart From Humans There Is Only One Other Creature That Has Sex For Pleasure. What is it? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Meniscus","incorrectAnswers":["Trochanter","Amygdala","Adenoid"],"question":"Which of these can be found in the knee?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Denmark","incorrectAnswers":["Pakistan","Israel","Greece"],"question":"Which of these countries has red on its flag?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Original Poster","incorrectAnswers":["On Prescription","Old Party","Overly Pregnant"],"question":"What do people mean when type the letters 'OP' in a message on the internet?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The French Revolution","incorrectAnswers":["The Russian Revolution","The Cuban Revolution","The Chinese Revolution"],"question":"Which revolution began in 1789?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Yellow","incorrectAnswers":["Black","Maroon","Orange"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Romania?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"15","incorrectAnswers":["9","10","14"],"question":"What is the sum of 1+2+3+4+5?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Samuel L. Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Paul Rudd","Clark Gregg","Tom Hiddleston"],"question":"Which actor plays the role of Nick Fury in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Contrology","incorrectAnswers":["Yoga","The Tibet Method","Balance Therapy"],"question":"What was pilates originally known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rammstein","incorrectAnswers":["Cascada","Blue System","Scorpions"],"question":"Which German industrial metal band released the studio album 'Herzeleid'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Safety","incorrectAnswers":["Sharp","Smooth","Bright"],"question":"What adjective is attached to both Gustave Pasch's match and Walter Hunt's pin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"South Dakota","incorrectAnswers":["Missouri","Wyoming","California"],"question":"Mount Rushmore is located in which state?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Guns N' Roses","incorrectAnswers":["Aerosmith","The Jackson 5","The Doobie Brothers"],"question":"Which band is Axl Rose the lead vocalist of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Carthage","incorrectAnswers":["Rome","Phoenicia","Egypt"],"question":"Who started the second Punic war?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Skin","incorrectAnswers":["Hair","Heart","Feet"],"question":"What part of the body is affected by dermatitis?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Wine","incorrectAnswers":["Nature","Chaos","Love"],"question":"Dionysus was the greek god of ______?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Cattywampus","incorrectAnswers":["Funambulist","Donkey Engine","Widdershins"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'askew'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Turkmenistan","incorrectAnswers":["Botswana","Pakistan","Mongolia"],"question":"Ashgabat is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nine Inch Nails","incorrectAnswers":["In This Moment","Nitty Gritty Dirt Band","Animal Collective"],"question":"Which American industrial rock band released the studio album 'The Downward Spiral'?","difficulty":"hard"},